本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第三集』
翻译  Jasmine雪
翻译  LyraL
翻译  ala365
翻译  小熊嘟嘟
翻译  小舞
时间轴  veryink
校对  苏小黛
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
区区六个守卫
No more than six guards.
不足挂齿的防御  很好
Paltry defences. It's perfect.
这简直是轻而易举  我们走
Huh! These are easy pickings. Come on!
我说了  我不明白为什么要急着完婚
I just said, I don't understand the rush to get married.
你俩从小就青梅竹马
You've been sweethearts since you were children.
订婚了五年
Engaged for five years--
我可不觉得这是着急
I don't call that a rush.
布里奇特  如果他不是我的真命天子怎么办
Bridget? What if he isn't the one?
你三天后就要成婚了
You're getting married in three days.
你只是有点动摇而已
You're just having a wobble.
听着  现在好男人不只是稀少
Listen, good men aren't just rare right now;
他们几乎不存在
they're practically non-existent.
里昂提斯年轻  英俊
Leontes is young, good looking,
还是国王的护卫  拜托
and the king's champion, for goodness sake!
他是个好的伴侣  会守卫你父亲的土地
He's a good union, and he'll protect your father's land.
而且最重要的是
But most of all,
他是你母亲一直希望你嫁的郎君
he's the one your mother always wanted for you.
我已经和里昂提斯说好了
I've told Leontes,
无论我们去哪里
wherever we go,
我想要你跟我一起
I want you with me.
你不仅是我的表亲
You're not just my cousin;
你还是我最亲密的朋友
you're my closest friend.
-桂妮维尔  -父亲  能不能先敲门啊
- Guinevere! - Father, do you mind?!
我们得离开这里  我们被袭击了
We must leave here. We're being attacked.
快点  我们得离开
Come on, we must leave.
父亲  阻止他们  不能让他们这么做
Father, stop them! We can't just let them do this!
没时间争论了
This is no time to argue.
把东西放下
Put those things down!
放下我们的东西  滚蛋
Get out of our things and just go!
桂妮维尔  你斗不过他们的
Guinevere, you can't fight them!
他们人太多了
There's too many of them.
桂妮维尔  快走
Guinevere, now!
我们不能就这么走了
We can't just leave!
滚  否则我就要动手了
Leave before I hurt you!
我们走
Let's go!
这些人在干什么呢
What are all these people doing here?
他们想要什么
What do they want?
想要新国王的帮助
Favours from the new king.
殿下  能耽误您片刻吗
Your Highness, might I have a moment,
请允许我...
just to beg your indulgence--
-抱歉  -陛下
- Sorry. - Sire.
殿下  耽误您片刻
Your Highness, just a moment of your time.
兄弟  你弄错了  这才是你要找的人
Wrong brother; it's him you want.
-殿下  -我稍后再来见你
- Oh, Your Highness-- - I'll be with you soon.
或者派其他人来见你  我保证
Or someone will. I promise.
消息已经传出去了  子民蜂拥而来
The word has spread. The people are flocking.
很好
It's good.
-殿下  -里昂提斯  怎么了
- Your Highness. - Leontes. What's wrong?
怎么回事
What's happened?
强盗袭击了我们  殿下
Bandits attacked us, Your Highness.
他们抢走了一切
They took everything.
我们不能回去了  那里不安全
We can't go back there; it's not safe.
能让他们在此避难吗
Can we give them sanctuary here?
给他们找个房间  我为他们做担保
Find them rooms? I'll vouch for them.
不行  这不是旅馆
No. This isn't a lodge.
没问题
Of course.
你们可以选个自己喜欢的房间
You can choose whatever room you like.
可能不会很舒适  但你们在这里很安全
They won't be comfortable, but you'll be safe here.
谢谢
Thank you.
不过现在无法完婚了
But there will be no wedding now,
此刻正是她最需要你保护的时候
just when she most needed your protection.
你们要成婚了吗
You're due to be married?
-三天后  -那就在这里举行婚礼吧
- In three days. - Then it must be here.
-什么  不行  -为什么不行
- What? No. - Why not?
-你不想让他们待这里  -我改主意了
- You didn't want them to stay. - Oh, I changed my mind.
没什么比婚礼更让人有希望了
Nothing says hope like a wedding.
国王护卫成婚  这是个完美的象征
The marriage of the king's champion--a perfect symbol.
除非你反对  殿下
Unless you object, Your Highness?
不会  当然不会
No, of course not.
谢谢
Thank you.
你女儿和里昂提斯将在卡米洛特完婚
Your daughter and Leontes shall marry here at Camelot.
您真是位善人
You're very kind.
把锁砸开
Break the lock.
这里就是尤瑟折磨囚犯的地方啊
So this is where Uther tortured his prisoners.
你们曾把囚犯带来这里吗
Did you bring prisoners here?
不仅是囚犯
Not just prisoners;
任何违抗他的人都会被带到这里
anyone who crossed him.
退下
Leave us.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
薇薇安
Vivian.
过来
Come here.
-你为我父亲效命吗  -是的
- Did you serve my father? - Yes.
这些印记怎么来的
Where did you get these markings?
几百年前  罗马人将我家人带至此地
The Romans brought my family here as slaves,
我们是奴隶
hundreds of years ago.
罗马帝国毁灭时  别人告诉我的
I was told that when the Empire fell,
我们留了下来
we stayed.
这些印记来自我们的祖国
The markings are from our homeland.
告诉我你对尤瑟的看法
Tell me what you thought of Uther.
我敬重你父亲
I respected your father.
你喜欢他吗
Did you like him?
你畏惧他吗
Did you fear him?
我敬重你父亲
I respected your father.
我想要你为我做点事
I want you to do something for me.
去看看所有雇工
Go through the staff.
留下你信任的  赶走你不信任的
Everyone you trust, keep; anyone you don't, get rid of.
好的
All right.
这城堡需要新鲜空气
This castle needs new air.
最好多找些女工来
More women would be good.
不过先把这间屋子清理出来
But first have this room cleared.
那些东西别动
Except for those.
房间现在都是一团糟  不过
The chambers are in a poor state now, but
稍作修葺就行了
it'll just take a little work to improve them.
好了
There.
恕我直言  请问佣人在哪
Forgive me for asking, but where are all the servants?
我们该跟谁交代准备工作呢
Who do we talk to about the preparations?
这个嘛
Oh, well...
其实  没有任何...
...there aren't exactly any...
意思是只有我们
Just us, then?
好吧
Right.
好啊
Good.
好了
Okay.
你正是我们需要的
You are what we need.
卡米洛特的第一个婚礼
The first wedding of Camelot.
我要把你打扮成值得传颂的新娘子
I am going to make you a bride worthy of legend.
-您这么说我会脸红的  -你做得好
- You're going to make me blush. - You've done well.
里昂提斯跟你很般配
Leontes is an excellent match.
我一直这么跟她说来着
That's what I keep telling her.
-他还深得国王宠幸  -我知道
- And he has the king's favour. - I know.
我再也找不到比他更好的人了
I couldn't ask for anyone better.
来  到这来
Here, come.
你爱他吗
Do you love him?
我不确定我是否知道那个字的意思
I'm not sure I even know what that word means.
没关系  我当年也是
That's all right. I was the same.
不过  要知道  只要稍有点运气
But, you know, with a little luck,
假以时日  你就可能会爱上他
in time, you might fall in love with him.
即使没有  在你意识到这点之前
And if you don't, before you know it,
你就会生下他的骨肉  然后你便会
he'll give you children, and then you'll...
你会爱上他们全部
...you'll love them.
很难组建一支国王该有的军队
Hardly an army fit for a king.
与洛特之战  我们损失了不少好士兵
We lost a lot of good men during the fight with Lot.
迟早还会有人来参军的
Sooner or later others are going to come.
不过现在我们不堪一击
But right now we're vulnerable.
如果能征招到一位有经验战士
If we recruit an exceptional warrior,
就能鼓舞士气  也能整顿一下军风
it would boost our morale, shake things up a bit.
再来点运气  大家就都会闻风而至
Then with a bit of luck, everyone will hear about it and come.
你想到什么人选了吗
Anyone spring to mind?
也许有一个
Maybe.
高文  一位战士  我曾与之作战
Gawain, a warrior I fought against once.
我曾试着招他入伍  为尤瑟而战
I tried to recruit him to Uther's men,
但他拒绝了
but he refused.
那你凭什么觉得我们这次能说服他呢
What makes you think we get him this time?
时代变了  你不是一直这么跟我说吗
This is different. Isn't that what you keep telling me?
反正问一下也不会有何损失
No harm in asking.
有事吗
Can I help you?
我来此只为见国王
I'm here for the king only.
他姐姐命我带信给他
His sister sends a message.
你的姐姐  也是你的同盟
Your sister and ally
邀请你去你父亲的城堡
invites you to visit your father's castle.
她为你准备了盛宴
She's planning a feast in your honour.
如此盛情啊
Such hospitality.
所为哪般呢
Why?
我只是代为转述而已
I only relay what I am told.
我们接受邀请
Then we accept.
我们即刻就会启程
We'll ride out immediately.
她会很高兴的
She'll be delighted.
未跟我商榷之前  不要私自接受任何邀请
You don't accept anything without conferring with me.
我是国王
I'm the king
我意已决
and I made a decision.
我觉得这里还有很多工作要做
I think there's quite enough to be doing here.
比如主持婚礼吗
Like hosting a wedding?
摩根是我姐姐  我想要多了解她
Morgan's my sister. I want to get to know her better.
如果我连自己的家人都无法团结
If I can't unite my own family,
又怎么去统一这个国家
how am I going to unite the country?
我们在哪能找到这位战士
So, where do we find this warrior?
最后一次听到他的消息时
The last I heard of him,
他就住在离这里一日骑程的地方
he was a day's ride from here.
我注意到你看她时的表情了
I see the way you look at her,
那个桂妮维尔
Guinevere.
里昂提斯的桂妮维尔吗
Leontes' Guinevere?
你梦到过她
You dreamt of her.
-没有  -别对我撒谎
- No I didn't. - Don't lie to me.
你们以前见过吗
Have you met her before today?
加冕礼那天见过一次  仅此而已
At the coronation, that's all.
没在别的地方见过了
Nowhere else?
没有
No.
没在沙滩上见过吗
Not on a beach?
你为什么会觉得我在沙滩上见过她
Why do you think I met her on a beach?
因为我看到了
Because I saw it.
只是个梦  我梦到了她  没别的了
It was a dream. I had a dream of her; nothing else.
那就好  因为她是属于里昂提斯的
Good, because she belongs to Leontes.
没有谁是属于谁的
Nobody belongs to anyone.
不能让任何东西威胁到我们的大业
And nothing jeopardizes our work here,
尤其是女人
least of all a woman.
你觉得你有权利这么跟我说话吗
Do you think you have the right to talk to me like that?
你现在的一切成就
Everything you are right now
都归功于我
is because of me.
记住了
Remember that.
殿下驾临  倍感荣幸
Your Highness. I'm honoured.
谢谢
Thank you.
你做了些改动啊
You have made changes.
是的  这里需要女人的打理
Yes, it needed a woman's touch.
来吧  我想你晚饭前一定想放松一下
Come on. I'm sure you'd like to relax before dinner.
薇薇安会照顾你  带你去你的寝宫
Vivian will look after you and show you to your chambers.
梅林
Merlin,
你随我来
you're with me.
我很高兴你们接受了邀请
I'm so glad you accepted my invitation.
我没接受  是亚瑟
I didn't; Arthur did.
你不能让那男孩离开你的视线
You can't let the boy out of your sight.
保护他是我的职责
It's my job to protect him.
-我只是想了解他  -王位现在是他的了
- I simply want to know him. - The crown is his now.
我了解
I understand that.
那么你完全放弃对王位的争夺了吗
So you've abandoned your claim entirely.
我们到了
Here you are.
你的旧房间
Your old room.
当年你伺奉尤瑟时  就住在这里
From when you were Uther's lackey.
真令人印象深刻
Impressive.
我们怎么就没这样的膳食呢
And why don't we have meals like this?
谢谢你  薇薇安
Thank you, Vivian.
就算我想毒死你
If I wanted to poison you,
也不会浪费如此美味的鹌鹑汤
I wouldn't do it by wasting good quail soup.
亚瑟
So Arthur,
如今你已拥有了王位
now that you have the crown,
你会用它做什么呢
what will you do with it?
问得好
That's a good question.
那就用妙语作答让我折服吧
Then dazzle me with a good answer.
作为一个男人和一位国王的首要职责
"The first duty of a man and of a king
便是追寻和探索真理
is the seeking after and investigation of truth."
西塞罗说的
Cicero.
西塞罗-罗马最杰出的演说家  教育家
完全正确
That's right.
他真是个好学生
He's been a good student.
但你要怎样将这理论付诸于实践呢
But how do you apply that principle in practice?
在做决策之前
Before I make too many decisions,
我必须先了解我的王国
I must get to know my kingdom
了解我的子民
get to know its people.
他们也必须了解你
And they must get to know you.
我不知道你来了
I didn't know you were there.
刚才的宴会相当丰盛
That was quite a feast you gave us.
我只想和你待一会儿
I just wanted to spend some time with you.
我吃了很多
I've had a lot to eat
也喝多了
and drink.
别指望我会清醒很久
Can't promise I'll be awake for that long.
男人都那样
Men seldom are.
这是我们的父亲以前就寝的房间吗
Is this the room our father used to sleep in?
是的  和我母亲一起
Yes, with my mother.
那时我还很小
When I was very little.
跟我说说他的事
Tell me about him.
他...
He...
他是个伟大的战士
He was a great warrior.
他可以很和蔼
He could be kind.
但也可以很残忍
But he could also be cruel...
极其残忍
extremely cruel.
我知道我的出现让你很为难
I know my arrival was difficult for you.
但我很高兴
But I'm glad
我们今晚有了良好的开端...
we got to start again tonight...
很高兴我们能适当地进行相互了解
glad we could get to know each other properly.
是啊
Yes.
只是我...我并不了解你  亚瑟
It's just that I... I don't really know you, Arthur.
你是谁
Who are you?
我真的说不出来
I can't really tell.
随便问我点问题
Ask me anything.
有人告诉过你  你是个王子吗
Were you ever told you were the son of a king?
没有
No.
真的
Honestly.
我们的父亲去世后  梅林告诉我了一切
Until Merlin arrived just after our father's death,
之前我什么都不知道
I knew nothing.
你什么都不知道吗
You knew nothing?
是的
Yes.
那现在呢  你有什么期望
And now? What do you hope for?
那是什么
What's in there?
很抱歉  我弄伤你了吗
I'm so sorry. Did I hurt you?
没有
No.
没事
No, it's fine.
如果你不介意的话  我现在要睡了
Now, if you don't mind, i'd quite like to pass out.
当然
Of course.
晚安
Sleep well,
殿下
Your Highness.
叫我亚瑟就行了
Just Arthur.
好吧
Yes.
就叫你亚瑟
Just Arthur.
你那无畏的战士
So your fearless warrior
就住在这烂教堂里
lives in this burnt-out church.
是这地方  没错
This is the place; has to be.
你确定吗
And you're certain?
我们去看看  走吧
Let's find out. Come on.
有人吗
Hello?
你的国王需要你的服务
Your king requires your service.
我不认识什么国王
I don't recognize any king.
好吧  但他认识你
Well, he recognizes you.
并且他需要你效忠
And he demands your loyalty.
是你
You.
我告诉过你了
I've told you before,
我没兴趣效忠尤瑟
I'm not interested in serving Uther.
你说过他很棒
I thought you said he was good.
好像也不咋样
He's not that good.
卡米洛特有很多他这样的男人
Camelot's got plenty of men as good as him.
谁是卡米洛特
Who's Camelot?
那不是一个人  是个地方
It's not a who; it's a place.
那里是我的兄弟  亚瑟王  统治的国家
From where my brother, King Arthur, rules the country.
不是我瞧不起他  他不是国王
Not my bit, he doesn't.
你对他没有任何了解
You don't know anything about him.
不过你固步自封于此  不了解也不奇怪
Hardly surprising, if you shut yourself away here.
那他就是另一个自以为是国王的军阀
So he's another warlord who thinks he's a king.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
他是尤瑟亲生的
He's from Uther's bloodline.
那没什么值得骄傲的
That's nothing to be proud of.
他从瀑布中拔出了战神之剑
He pulled the sword of Mars from the waterfall.
你要我怎么做  欢呼吗
What do you want me to do? Cheer?
他打败了洛特王
He vanquished King Lot.
洛特死了吗
Lot's dead?
你们想找我做什么
So what do you want with me?
我们需要一名强大的战士
We need a strong warrior to return with us,
帮我们训练其他人
help train others.
我们专程从海边过来寻访你的
We came from the coast to look for you.
你们是在浪费时间
Then you wasted your time.
我看也是
Obviously.
看来今晚得睡在这里了
We're going to have to sleep here.
给钱才能睡
Not unless you pay me.
你到底怎么了
This is what's happened to you?
从一个倍受尊崇的战士
From a respected warrior to
沦落到催讨房租的吝啬鬼
demanding payment for lodging.
这太令人震惊了
It's impressive.
再也没什么值得为之而战了
There's nothing worth fighting for anymore.
哪里能赚钱我就去哪里
I take money where I can get it.
这是主的居所
This is the Lord's dwelling.
这代表我有权住这里
And this grants me access.
好吧
Fine.
但天一亮  你们就得离开
But come first light, you leave.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
桂妮维尔
It's Guinevere.
那次杀戮  他倍感骄傲
He was so proud at that kill.
那只雄鹿垂死挣扎了很久
The stag refused to die for a long time.
尤瑟喜爱战斗
Uther loved to fight.
我记得
I remember.
那只受伤的鹿跳得最高
The wounded deer jumps highest,
抗争最顽强
strives the hardest.
我不是只受伤的鹿  梅林
I'm not a wounded deer, Merlin.
我也不是国王的战利品
And I'm not a king's trophy.
很好  让我们为此喝一杯
Good. Let's drink to that.
你还记得年幼时的我吗
Do you remember me as a child?
不记得
No.
可我记得你
I remember you.
有一次父王染病
You came once when my father was ill.
幸得你妙手回春
You cured him.
我治愈的人数不胜数
I've cured many.
我还因此仰慕于你
I adored you for that.
我跟父王说  长大之后要下嫁给你
I told him that when I grew up, I'd marry you.
-你可知父王当时说什么  -不知道
- And do you know what he said? - No.
他说  得梅林者得天下
He said, "Marry Merlin and everything will be yours.
但你会为他迷失心智
Except your soul".
言重了
A little harsh.
梅林  我能闻到你的气息
I can smell you, Merlin.
是你杀了尤瑟  我早该想到
It was you. I should've known.
酒里有毒  酒里有毒
The wine. The wine!
亚瑟  你不能进来
Arthur... You can't be in here.
别这样
Don't do this.
我必须来见你
I have to see you.
我要跟你谈谈
I have to talk to you.
我不能这么做
I can't.
告诉我 你不曾想念过我
Tell me you're not thinking of me,
那我马上离开
and I'll leave you alone.
我在海滩等你
Meet me at the beach.
-我不知能否赶到  -我会等你
- I don't know if I can. - I'll wait for you.
-如果我去不了...  -我会等你
- If I'm not there-- - I'll wait for you.
放开我
Get off me!
亚瑟在哪里
Where's Arthur?
亚瑟
Arthur!!
放开我
Let me go.
你每次醒来都这般狂躁吗
Do you always wake in such a bad mood?
-你拿了什么  -一些脚趾甲而已
- What are you taking? - Just a few toenails.
我还为你修剪了胡须
And I trimmed your beard.
看你一副蓬头垢面的模样
You were looking dishevelled.
-亚瑟呢  -走了
- Where's Arthur? - Gone.
-他昨夜就走了  -你抓我做什么
- He left in the night. - Why are you holding me?
我是在为我弟弟着想  你可能心怀不轨
I'm worried for my brother. You may be dangerous.
我心怀不轨
I'm dangerous?
我看到了你对尤瑟的所作所为
I saw what you did to Uther.
你居然杀死了自己的父亲
You murdered your own father.
父亲
Father!
他根本不配被称为父亲
He never deserved to be called a father.
父亲对女儿绝不会像尤瑟对我这样
Fathers don't do to their daughters what Uther did to me.
他到底对你做了什么  摩根
Ooh! What did he do to you, Morgan?
他使我变得强大  这点我倒心存感激
He made me strong. And for that I'm grateful.
你能做的...
What you can do--
你学到的那种能量
this power you've learned--
不会使你变得强大
that doesn't make you strong;
只会令你元气大伤  代价斐然
it hurts you; it costs.
梅林  你别想吓唬我
Don't try and frighten me, Merlin!
这是真的
It's true.
你此刻恐已受控于它
You're in its grip even now.
你可能还未意识到
Oh, you don't realize it,
其实你已极其脆弱
but you've never been more vulnerable in your life.
可现在被锁住的人不是我
I'm not the one tied up here, am I?
-你以为我逃不走吗  -那就让我见识一下
- You think I can't free myself? - Then do it.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
-我不屑耍雕虫小技  -因为你做不到
-I don't perform tricks. - Because you can't.
因为我足够强大  大可不必这么做
Because I'm strong enough to choose not to.
做了才能显示你更强大
It would be stronger to choose to do it.
随心所欲  这就是你所谓的本事
To do it at will? Is that what you can do?
-当然  -见识一下
- Yes. - Show me.
让我见识一下你的本事
Show me what you can do.
是你
That's you.
这就是年幼的你
That's you as a child.
够了
Enough!
你的代价太大了
The price will be too high.
不  这点算不得什么
No. Not too high at all.
放我走
Let me go.
放开我
Untie me.
摩根
Morgan.
Morgan!!
-别嫁给他  -别胡说
- Don't marry him. - Don't be ridiculous.
-你们不配  -你根本不了解我
- He's not right for you. - You don't even know me.
我们之间有种难言的情愫
There was something between us.
在加冕礼上
At the coronation.
还有这里
And here,
每次我们相遇之时
when we met.
我没感觉到
I didn't feel it.
别再否认了
Stop denying it.
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
承认我们之间也许会有些什么
That there could be something between us.
-我就要嫁人了  -不要
- I'm getting married. - Don't.
你是以国王的身份命令我吗
Are you asking me as my king?
还是个仅仅相遇过两次
Or as a complete stranger who's only met me twice
却自以为能左右我的陌生人
who has decided that he can order me about?
你若不是深有同感  为何要来这里
If you don't feel the same way, then why did you come?
我来让你打消念头
To ask you to stop.
在卡米洛特时你为何不说
You could've said that at Camelot.
你来
You came...
...是因为你也盼着这一刻
...because you wanted this too.
不
No.
或许
Maybe.
再吻
Again.
不要
Stop.
他会知道的
He'll know.
你怎么哭了
Why are you crying?
因为我盼着这一刻
Because I want this.
仅此一次
Just once,
just once,
一次
就一次...
just once...
别碰我的东西
You get away from that stuff.
马可·奥里利乌斯
Marcus Aurelius.
西方哲学家 罗马皇帝
你读过
You've read it?
伟大的哲学帝王之一
One of the great philosopher kings.
我...
I'm, uh...
-我有些地方看不懂  -哪里不懂
- struggling a little. - Where are you up to?
从父亲的声望和对他的追忆中
"From the reputation and remembrance of my father,
我学到了谦恭勇武
"I learnt modesty and a manly character.
从兄长西弗勒斯那里  我学会了疼爱亲人
"And from my brother Severus, I learnt to love my kin,
热爱真理与正义
and to love truth and justice."
你很棒
You're very good.
谁教你的
Who taught you?
我父亲
My father.
你呢
What about you?
自学
Teaching myself.
这可不简单啊
That's quite a task.
为什么想学
So why bother?
想有所提高
To be better.
你说的没错
You were right about him.
他的确是完美的人选
He'd be perfect.
要是他自己知道就好了
If only he knew it.
如果我去
If I did come,
有一个条件
one condition:
教我读这本书
teach me how to read this book.
等我们完成卡米洛特的大业时
By the time we're finished at Camelot,
你就能写书了
you'll be ready to write a book.
结束了
It's over.
就这样吧
This was it--
只此一次
the once.
从此我们必须缄口不言
Now we must never talk of it.
永远不能让他知道
He must never know.
我得去准备我的婚礼了
I have to get ready for my wedding.
很好  这里放一个  那边也放一个
Oh, good, yes. Put one here and just put one there.
-你俩换一下  -好的  夫人
- Oh, I need you to switch. - Yes, madam.
再高些
Higher!
再拿高一点
Bring it up a bit more.
把这个吊上去
You're going to put that up?
好的  再高点
Oh, yes, higher.
再高一点点  好了  就这样
And a little bit higher. Okay, stop.
他会知道的
He'll know.
今晚  里昂提斯就会知道的
Tonight, Leontes will know.
我们该怎么办
What are we going to do?
我们得想办法解决  里昂提斯是个好人
We have to fix this. Leontes is a good man.
我知道
I know.
天哪
Oh, my God.
把匕首给我
Give me the knife.
-它已经死了  -我们有办法了
- It's already dead. - We can make it right.
-把酒袋给我  -你要做什么
- Get me the wine sack. - What are you going to do?
我们该回去了
We have to get back.
这就走了吗
You're leaving?
你展示给我看的  是你全部的本事吗
What you showed me is that all you've learnt?
目前是的
For now.
你不懂你所滥用的法术
You don't understand the forces you're messing with.
但我懂  你不会如愿的
I do. You won't get what you want.
我们只需耐心地拭目以待  不是吗
We'll just have to wait and see, won't we?
我学会了耐心
I've learned to be patient.
告诉国王  这里永远是他的家
Tell the king he has a home here, always.
摩根  摩根
Morgan? Morgan.
愿你尽快恢复健康和理智
May your health and judgment return promptly.
开门
Open the gates!
最后的自由之夜  里昂提斯
Last night of freedom, Leontes!
你很快就是有妇之夫了
You'll soon be a married man!
别别别  放我下来
No! Put me down! No!
我是高文
Gawain.
亚瑟
Arthur.
显然  我现在替你卖命
Apparently I work for you now.
走咯
Here we go, son!
信使送来了这个  没说是谁送的
Messenger brought this. Didn't say who it was from.
-想现在打开吗  -当然
- Do you want to open it now? - Yes.
真美
Oh, that is so beautiful.
我们该配上丝带  这样你就能戴了
We should put it on a ribbon so that you can wear it.
-祝您健康  陛下  -殿下
- Your health, Sire. - Your Highness.
殿下
Your Highness.
亚瑟  殿下
Arthur, Your Highness,
我有一事相求
there's something I wanted to ask you.
您愿意为我们主持婚礼吗
Would you preside over our ceremony?
我本来请了村里的长者来主持
I've arranged to have an elder from our village do it,
但若能由国王主持  那将更有意义
but it would mean so much more if the king would honour it.
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
若风暴席卷我们的土地
*And if the storm blows through our land *
我愿做你的避风港
*I'll be your shelter *
可否做我的灯塔
*If you'll be my light *
当凛冬将至
*And if the world should fall to winter *
我将成为你的妻
*I'll be your wife *
可否做我的灯塔
*If you'll be my light *
里昂提斯真走运
Lucky Leontes.
当乌云漫天
*And if the skies should cloud to darkness *
我愿做你的阳光
*I'll be your sun *
咱们来瞧瞧你内心的真实所想  弟弟
Let's see what's truly in your heart, brother.
愿此婚戒
May these rings stand forever
成为你们结合与忠诚的
as a symbol of your unity
永恒象征
and fidelity.
愿你们白头偕老
May you live and grow old together,
发现永恒的
knowing only the truth
爱的真理
of undying love.
在众人的见证之下
By witness of all of those present...
我宣布你们
...I confirm you...
成为夫妻
...as man and wife.
里昂提斯  桂妮维尔  恭喜
Leontes and Guinevere! Leontes and Guinevere!
吾妻
My wife.
吾夫
My husband.